United Association of Plumbers and Steamfitters, Local 305 Records 1984.0034
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
United Association of Plumbers and Steamfitters, Local 305 Records
undated, 1934-1983
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0034
2.3 Linear Feet
The United Association of Plumbers and Steamfitters, Local 305, was established on 17 June 1910 by a group of piping tradesmen. Three of its founders were William Tomlinson, Charles A. Smith and Frank Kennedy.
Access
The collection is open and available for research with the exception of Series II. Researchers interested in the materials in Series II must consult with the curator for access.
Acquisition Information
The records of the United Association of Plumbers and Steamfitters, Local 305, were deposited with the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division (now Archives & Special Collections) of the University of Connecticut Libraries by the Local in July 1984.
Arrangement
Series I: Minutes (1934-1964) consists of 13 volumes of meeting minutes, as well as programs and a guest book from the union's 50th anniversary celebration. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series II: Application for Membership Cards (undated) is arranged alphabetically by last name. [RESTRICTED]
Series III: Administrative Records (1952-1983) contains correspondence (arranged alphabetically by year), financial reports, cash receipts statements, and treasurer's records.
History
The United Association of Plumbers and Steamfitters, Local 305, (>Norwich, CT) was established on 17 June 1910 by a group of piping tradesmen. Three of its founders were William Tomlinson, Charles A. Smith and Frank Kennedy, who were still members fifty years later. Mr. Smith was the first president of the Local and Mr. Kennedy was the first secretary.
With the passage of time and new improvements in the industry, Local 305 Journeymen traveled to Massachusetts, upper New York State, Long Island and other places where their skills were in demand. Projects included: industrial plants and power houses, hospitals and educational institutions, United States Reservations, and freighters. Local 305 contributed to the installation of a major part of the sanitary and heating systems at the U.S. Coast Guard Academy in New London, Connecticut.
The Depression was a difficult time for the Local and membership fell to only seven members. Union workers took a fifteen cents per hour reduction to help stimulate trade business. A membership drive subsequently stabilized the Local.
The parent organization for Local 305 is the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipefitting Industry of the United States and Canada.
Scope and Content
The collection includes administrative, financial and legal records of the local, in addition to several publications and pamphlets.
Administrative records; History; Labor unions; Newsletters; Connecticut (state); Plumbing; Correspondence; Plumbers; Financial Records; Norwich (inhabited place); United Association of Plumbers and Steamfitters. Local 305
- Series I: Minutes, 1934-1964
  - 1935 January 9 - 1942 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1942 September 18 - 1946 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1947 January 10 - 1951 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1952 February 15 - December 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1952 February 15 - December 16 (drafts) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1953 January 6 - December 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1954 January 5 - 1956 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1956 January 3 - December 18 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1957 January 15 - December 17 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1958 January 10 - December 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1959 January 20 - December 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1960 January 19 - 1961 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1962 January 16 - 1964 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Various drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Guest Book, [1960?] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Programs, [1960?] (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II: Application for Membership Cards, undated, 1956-1967
  Access
  Researchers must consult with the curator to gain access to the materials in series II.
  - A - Z, undated, 1956-1967 (Box 2)
- Series III: Administrative Records, undated, 1952-1983
  - Agreements, undated, 1958-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - American Federation of Labor Pamphlet: "The Significance of State Laws Prohibiting Union Security", 1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Constitution of Connecticut Federation of Labor, A.F.L., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1955
    - A - D, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - E - M, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - N - Z, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - A - M, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - N - Z, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Financial Reports (United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipefitting Industry of the United States and Canada), 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Forms (blank), undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - General Officers' Weekly Newsletter, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Statement of cash receipts, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Treasurer's records, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Working Wage Agreement, 1953 October (Box 3, Folder 31)